Horvitz, Aaron Collection of Detroit Edison Company and Utility Workers Union of America, Local 223 Arbitration Files 5128
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Aaron Horvitz Collection of Detroit Edison Company and Utility Workers Union of America, Local 223 Arbitration Files
1914- 1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Horvitz, Aaron
Detroit Edison Company
Utility Workers Union of America
5128
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Detroit Edison Company and Utility Workers Union of America, Local 223: arbitration files, 1914-1953.
3119257
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 20, 2012
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, October 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Detroit Edison was part of a large holding company called North American Edison Company. North American's stock had once been one of the twelve component stocks of the May 1896 original Dow Jones Industrial Average. North American Company was broken up by the Securities and Exchange Commission, following the United States Supreme Court decision of April 1, 1946.
After that Detroit Edison operated independently, and publicly traded on the New York Stock Exchange, under the ticker symbol DTE through the mid-1990s. In early 1996, it became an operating subsidiary of the new holding company, DTE Energy Company, which replaced Detroit Edison Company on the stock exchange, and took over the trading ticker symbol.
Scope and Contents
This was a voluntary arbitration proceeding with the arbitrator, Mr. Aaron Horowitz selected as the mutual choice of the parties from the American Arbi-tration Assn. Mr. Donald F. Kigar served as consultant for the company and Robert Reynolds for the union. Hearings were begun in Detroit on Deo. L4, 1953.
Issue: "Did the company violate the agreement by unilaterally transferring certain Production Dept. Maintenance employees of this named department into newly named Construction and Maintenance Department and merging them with employees of the last named department in a centralized maintenance group, all of which subjected a large number of employees to changes in wages, hours, and working conditions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3051: Albert Martin Papers /4212: Kheel Center Current Documents Correspondence 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2 5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 5678: Gabriel Alexander Additional Arbitration Files 5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents 5916: Peter J. Cioni Labor Agreement Collection 6046: Archives Union File (AUF) 6178/003: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 3) 6178/010: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 10) 6178/018: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 18) /3052: John W. McConnell Papers /4222: Matt Kelly Papers 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5049: Waldo J. Nielsen Collection of Utility Workers Organization in New York Materials 5488 C: BRAC Additional Records 5493: Elmer E. Hilpert Arbitration Papers 5538: James C. Hill Arbitration Files 5539: Benjamin H. Wolf Additional Arbitration Files 5576: S. Stanley Alderfer Arbitration Files 5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications 5602: Gabriel Alexander Additional Arbitration Files 5637: Sidney A. Wolff Additional Arbitration Files 5678: Gabriel Alexander Additional Arbitration Files 5712: Burton B. Turkus Arbitration Files 5733: Peter Seitz Arbitration Files 5735: BRAC Additional Records 5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents 5916: Peter J. Cioni Labor Agreement Collection 6030: Archival Collective Bargaining Agreements File 6035: Constitution Collection 6091: Marcia Greenbaum Papers 6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection 6141: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 6178/010: BLS Collection of Collective Bargaining Agreements (Part 10)
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Detroit Edison Company; Utility Workers Union of America; Horowitz, Aaron
3119257
- Union Exhibits and Company Exhibits (Box 1)
  - Before the American arbitration Association - submission by the union (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Answering statement of Detroit Edison Company (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agreement of the two parties, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents
    August 11, 1953
  - Wage Schedules, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    September 7, 1953
  - Agreement, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    November 14, 1952
  - Transcript of the hearing before Mister Kigar in accordance with Third Step Grievance procedure (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorandum of authorities submitted by the Detroit Edison Company (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Map of Detroit Edison Service Area (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chart of stockholders and employees since 1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Organization chart of Detroit Edison (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Power Plant maps (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Summation of major equipment in systems (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Shrinking Reserves, 1942-1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Shrinking Reserves, 1926-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Shrinking Reserves, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Estimates Reserves in 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Daily peak load, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fluctuation in Number of Hourly Rated Employees (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter from Mr. Cisler outlining introduction of centralized maintenance, 1953; Letter (Box 1, Folder 19)
    October 2, 1953
  - Letter from Kaufman to O'Dell on centralized maintenance, 1953; Letter (Box 1, Folder 20)
    September 2, 1953
  - Letter from Kaufman to O'Dell on centralized maintenance, 1953; Letter (Box 1, Folder 21)
    September 10, 1953
  - Amendment Number 1 to agreement of August 11, 1953 offered to Union (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter to O'Dell from Porter on formation of temporary troubling turbine maintenance crew, 1951; Letter (Box 1, Folder 23)
    January 11, 1951
  - Company minutes of Negotiation Meeting January 30, 1947; Letter of April 15, 1947; Exhibit 24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    January 30; April 15
  - Letter of June 10, 1947; Exhibit 25 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    June 10, 1947
  - Grievance file on Delray traveling boiler, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Agreement, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    October 16, 1950
  - Unions proposal for changes in the agreement of October 1950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Historical development of Article IX - Section 3 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Memo of Understanding, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    May 29, 1953
  - Memo of Understanding, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    July 16, 1953
  - Review of Production Maintenance Practice and a proposed change (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Agreement with Production Department, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    July 1, 1943
  - Agreement. Field Division of the Construction Bureau, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    September 28, 1943
  - Agreement, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    July 1, 1944
  - Agreement, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    November 1, 1946
  - Agreement, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    March 10, 1948
  - Agreement, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    August 31, 1949
  - Agreement, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Historical Development of Article VIII, Section 4, Work sharing (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Historical development of Article VI, Section 4, Shift schedules - Section 5 Non-shift schedules (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Chart of relevant contract provisions (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - See Exhibits 24 and 25 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Notice of Job Vacancy for Flue Blower (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Notice of Job Vacancy for Laborer, male (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Notice of Job Vacancy for Flue Blower and Ash Handler (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Notice of Job Vacancy for Rigger in the Construction Department (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Job Time of Stoker Trader in the Production Department (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Notice of Job Vacancy for Construction in Welding Department (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Job for Carpenter, male, Construction Department (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Job for Mechanic, male (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Job for Turbine Room Helper (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Job for Plumber, male (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Job for Leader in Sunstation Department of Electrical Maintenance Division (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Job Vacancy - Leader Schedule (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Notice to Shift Leaders, etc., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    March 5, 1948
  - Shift Leaders - Job bidding for Journeyman, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    June 3, 1948
  - Shift Leaders - Job bidding for journeyman, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    May 27, 1948
  - Schedule, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    June 23 1949
  - Formal Grievance filled by union under grievance 1 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Union presentation to the membership (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Analysis of notices of job vacancies; Brief of the Detroit Edison Company; Union Memorandum; Opinion and Award; Union's Dissent to Arbitration Award (Box 1, Folder 63)